Guide to the Urie Bronfenbrenner papers, [ca. 1960-2011]
Bronfenbrenner, Urie papers, [ca. 1960-2011]
- Series III. Published Works
  - "Some Antecedents and Correlates of Differential Patterns of Response to Pressure from Peers and Adults Among Israeli Kibbutz Children.", 1972 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - "American Family: Trends and Pressures.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - "An Emerging Theoretical Perspective for Research in Human Development.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - "Children, Families, and Social Policy: An American Perspective.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - "A Comparison Between Three Movements of Kibbutzim by Means of Mazkir-Interview.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - "Early Childcare in the USA.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - "Family and Child in American Development.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - "Family Authority Structures and the Disposition to Inform on Peers Among Urban Children in West Germany and Israel.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - "The Impact of Socialization Setting and Ethnic Origin on Autonomy and Locus of Control in Israeli Pre-Adolescents.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - "Israeli Kibbutz Gossip.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - "Israel: Social Structure and Change.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "A Comparison of Kibbutz and Moshav by Means of Mazkir-Interview.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Last Lecture in HD& FS 115, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - "Making Children Human.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "New Zealand Adolescents' Parent-Peer Orientation and Parent Perceptions Compared with English and American.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - "Open Classrooms vs. Open Schools.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - "Sex Differences in the Relationship Between Socialization and Informing Behavior in City and Kibbutz Children in Israel.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - "The Social Ecology of Human Development.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - "Why Israel?", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - "The American Family Act: Suggested Principles and Provisions.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - "Instruments and Israel.", 1973 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    Bibliography
  - "Socializations in the Israeli Kibbutz.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - "Conformity to Peer-Sponsored Misconduct at Fourth-Grade Levels.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence with the Dryden Press, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - "Developmental Research, Public Policy, and the Ecology of Childhood.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - "An Ecological Approach to the Issue of Personality Consistency and Situation Specificity: Open and Closed Social Networks.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - "Eleven Blind Americans and the Chinese Child", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - "Examining American Values.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - "Experimental Human Ecology.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - "From Another Planet.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Influences on Human Development, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - "Intervention.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - "Is Early Intervention Effective?", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 53)
    Condensed Version
  - "The Origins of Alienation.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - "Socialization Practices of Parents, Teachers, and Peers in Israel: The Kibbutz vs. the City.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - "Television in the Classroom.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - "Three Worlds of Childhood.", 1974 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - "Alienation and the American Psychologist.", 1975-09-1975-10 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    In the APA Monitor, Vol. 6, No. 9/10
  - "Anomalous Reactions to Social Pressure of Israeli and Soviet Children Raised in Family vs. Collective Settings.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 59)
    In the Journal of Personality and Social Psychology, Vol. 32, No. 3
  - "The Challenge of Social Change to Public Policy and Developmental Research.", 1975-04-12 (Box 10, Folder 60)
    Prepared for the President's Synaposium on Child Development and Publich Policy. Society for Research in Child Development, Denver, CO
  - "The Changing American Family.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - "Chinas Kinder.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    In Die Grundschule
  - "Decisions Made in Experimental Conflict: Situations by Rural Pupils of 8th Grade in Elementary School.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 63)
    Sándor Komlósi, Teachers' Training College, Pécs, Hungary
  - "The Ecology of Human Development: a Research Perspective.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - "The Ecology of Human Development in Retrospect and Prospect.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - "Field Dependence Among Eastern and Western Children.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Introduction to Bert Brim., 1975 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - "Nature with Nurture: A Reinterpretation of the Evidence.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 68)
    In Race and IQ. ed. Ashley Montagu. NY: Oxford University Press
  - "The Next Generation of Americans.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - "Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 70)
    Papers read at the annual General Meeting, Vol. 119, No. 6, Philadelphia, PA
  - "Sex Role Differentiation Among Israeli Children from Two Social Settings: Kibbutz and City.", 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - "Socialization of Social Competence.", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 72)
    Iris Levin
  - "The Socialization on Moral Judgment and Behavior in Cross-Culture Perspective.", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 73)
    In Man and Morality: Theory, Research and Social Issues, ed. Thomas Lickona. Holt, Rinehart and Winston
  - "Who Cares for America's Children?", 1975 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    Presented at the Joint House-Senate Hearing on the Child and Family Services Act of 1975
  - "America's Children and Families: An International Perspective.", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - "Day Care in Context: An Ecological Perspective on Research and Public Policy.", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    Prepared for the Office of the Assistant Secretary of Planning and Evaluation, Department of Health, Education and Welfare
  - "The Disturbing Changes in the American Family.", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    Published in the Fall
    Search at the State University of New York, Vol.2, No.1
  - Ecological Validity in the Study of Human Development, 1976-09 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    1976 APA Convention, Washington, DC
  - "The Effect of Russian vs. Hebrew Instructions on the Reaction to Social Pressure of Russian-born Israeli Children.", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Epilogue, the National Elementary Principal, 1976-07-1976-08 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    Vol. 55, No. 6
  - "The Experimental Ecology of Education.", 1976-12 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    In the Teachers' College Record, Vol. 78, No. 2
  - "The Family Circle: A Study in Fragmentation.", 1976-05-1976-06 (Box 10, Folder 82)
    In the National Elementary Principal, Vol. 55, No. 5
  - "Is Early Intervention Effective?", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    German Edition
  - "Meeting the Needs of Families with Young Children: A Research Program.", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 84)
  - "Who Cares for America's Children", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - "Adolescents Educatied in Israel and in the USSR: Differences in Moral Judgment.", 1976 (Box 10, Folder 86)
    Avner Ziv, Abraham Shani, and Shoshana Nebenhaus, Tel-Aviv University. In the Journal of Cross-Culture Psychology
  - "Head Start Reminiscences" (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "Experimental Human Ecology:A Reorientation to Theory and Research on Socialization" - Reviews, 1970's (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Publications and papers from "Cross-Cultural Studies in Socialization", 1970's (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - "The Effect of Russian Versus Hebrew Instructions on the Reaction to Social Pressure of Russian-Born Israeli Children", 1975 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "The American Family - Who Cares?", 1976 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - APA letter, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - "Ein Bezugsrahmen fur okologische Sozialisationsforschung", 1976 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Garbarino and Bronfenbrenner, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - "Mother and Father in Kibbutz and City" - Shouval, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Toward a National Policy, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - "Who Cares for America's Children?", 1976 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Doing Your own Thing - Our Undoing", 1977 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - "The Disturbing Changes in the American Family", 1977 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - "Ecological Factors in Human Development", 1977 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - "Lewinian Space and Ecological Substance" - The Kurt Lewin Memorial Award Presentation, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - "Nobody Home: the Erosion of the American Family", 1977 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Parent and Peer Orientation of Adolescents - Pat Martin, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "The Social Role of the Child in Ecological Perspective, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - "Socialization Practices of Parents, Teachers and Peers in Israel: Kibbutz, Moshav and City", 1977 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Testimony submitted to the Subcommittee on Employee Ethics and Utilization Committee on Post Office and Civil Service - "Strengthening Families Through Flexible Work Schedules", 1977 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - "Toward an Experimental Ecology of Human Development", 1977 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - "Developmental Trends in Reaction to Social Pressure From Adults versus Peers" Bengt-Erik Anderson, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - "Educational Reform for a Changing Society", 1978 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - "Sociometric Paper. City vs. Kibbutz", 1978 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - "Transcultural Code of Molar Activities", 1978 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Visit to Charlotte, North Carolina - Junior League, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - "Who Lives on Sesame Street?", 1978 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - "Who Needs Parent Education", 1978 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - "Beyond the Deficit Model in Child and Family Policy", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - "Class in a Classless Society", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - "Contexts of Child Rearing Problems and Prospects", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - "A Curriculum for Caring", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - "Developmental Changes in Intimate Friendship with Same-Sex and Opposite-Sex Friends", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Johnson and Johnson Forward, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - "On Families and Schools", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - "Recreating Human Ecology", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - "Support Systems for Working Parents Some Problems and Proposals", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - "Trends in Social Science Research on Children: The Status, the Situation and the Role of Children in the USA" symposium in Texas, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - "What Shapes Children: Enduring Irrational Involvement", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - "Who Care for Children", 1979 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - "Erziehungsstilforschung" Garbarino and Bronfenbrenner, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - "Intelligence in Black and White", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - "On Making Human Beings Human", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - "U.S. Families Need Public Supports", 1980 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - "Children and Families: The Silent Revolution", 1981 (Box 11, Folder 44A)
  - "Children and Families", 1981;1984 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - "The Mismeasure of Man", 1981 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - "Options in Education" Portrait of Urie Bronfenbrenner National Public Radio, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - "Options in Education" Portrait of American Adolescence" National Public Radio (Parts I, II, IV and V), 1977-10 (Box 11, Folder 47A)
  - Play Review - "The Dreamers", 1981 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - "Who is Getting Cut? Some Unintended Effects", 1981 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - "What is an Indirect Effect?", 1981 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - "The Changing Family in a Changing World America, First?", 1982 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - "Child Development: the Hidden Revolution", 1982 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - "New Images of Children, Families and America", 1982 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - "Work and Family Through Time and Space", 1982 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - "Beyond Policies Without People: An Ecological Perspectives on Child and Family Policy", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - "The Changing American Family", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - "Citation Classic", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - "The Context of Development and the Development of Context", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - "The Evolution of Environmental Models in Developmental Research" 1983 Reviews (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - "Family Policy and Family Life: Friends or Enemies?", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Forward to paper "The Impact of Work Schedules on the Family" written by Urie Bronfenbrenner, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - "Okologische Perspektiven zur Kinder und Familienpolitik", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 62)
  - "On Making Human Beings Human", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - "Our Schools Need a Curriculum for Caring", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 64)
  - Permission to publish Brigham Young Commencement Address (Box 11, Folder 65)
  - "Working and Watching: Maternal Employment Status and Parents' Perceptions of their Three-Year-Old Children", 1983 (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - "The Changing Family in a Changing World: America First?", 1984 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - "Child, Family and Community", 1984 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - "Contributions to a History of Developmental Psychology" forward by Urie Bronfenbrenner, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Dayton, Ohio - correspondence and article about Urie Bronfenbrenner's speaking engagement, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 70)
  - "Developing Character: Transmitting Knowledge", 1984 (Box 11, Folder 71)
  - "The Graphic Analysis of Moderating Effects", 1984 (Box 11, Folder 72)
  - "Innovator" the University of Michigan, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 73)
  - "Mirror Image in Soviet American Relations", 1984 (Box 11, Folder 74)
  - "New Worlds for Families", 1984 (Box 11, Folder 75)
  - Statement for Cornell, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 76)
  - "Three Worlds of Childhood Linking Home, School, and Community" Adelaide, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 77)
  - "Children: Needs and Rights" by Vincent Greaney, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - "Contributions to a History of Developmental Psychology-forward by Urie, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - "Don't Forget to Take the Cupcake Out of the Oven: Prospective Memory, Strategic Time-Monitoring and Context", 1985 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - "Freedom and Discipline Across the Decades", 1985 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - G. Stanley Hall Award Presentation, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 82)
  - "Infancia", 1985 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - "I am honored to be here today...", 1985 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - "The Parent/Child Relationship and Our Changing Society", 1985 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Pearce Williams - letter and article, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Random House Chapter, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - "The Social and Affective Development of Black Children", 1985 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - "Three Worlds of Childhood", 1985 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Dean's Ad Hoc Committee on Implementation of College Objectives, 1970's (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Mayor's Committee on the Collegetown Investigation, 1972-04 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Human Ecology Institutes, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Educational Policy Committee - Arts and Sciences, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Israeli Research Grant, 1969-1970's (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Israeli Conference Meetings, 1970's (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Israeli Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Israeli Correspondence, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Israeli Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Israeli Project, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Israeli Study - Office of Education (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - China Correspondence - National Academy of Sciences Trip, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - "The Chinese Family" (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - China Grant - Russell Sage, 1972-1974 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - China Grant - Russell Sage, 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Little Red Soldiers - Notes on interviews with adult leaders (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - China File - Correspondence, Memoranda (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Families and Women in Marriage (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Cross-Cultural Studies of Socialization - 2 Chinas and 1 Japan, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - The Roots of Alienation Among College Students - A Proposal for an Empirical Study (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - White House Conference on Youth - Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - White House Conference on Youth - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - White House Conference on Children and Youth, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - White House Conference on Youth, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - White House Conference on Youth, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - White House Conference on Youth, 1970 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Assignment Children (UNICEF) (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence - U.S. Congress, 1960-1969 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Task Force on Child Development, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Task Force on Child Development, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Task Force on Child Development, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Task Force on Child Development, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Task Force on Child Development, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Task Force on Urban Education, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Task Force on Urban Education, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Moscow Round Table (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Cornell Tompkins Day Care Project, 1973;1977 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Some Unsocialized Thoughts About Socialization (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Toward an Integrated Theory of Personality, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Family Structure and Development, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - "Socialization and Social Class Through Space and Time", 1950s (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - "Familienautoritatsstruktur und jugendliches verhallen" with Edward Devereux, Jr., 1959-11 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - On the Concept of Modeling in Interpersonal Perception (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Freudian Theories of Identification and their Derivatives, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - A Social Psychologist Looks at the Soviet Union, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lecture Notes/Lee Salk, 1960-1963 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - The Challenge of the New Soviet Man, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Wandel der americkanischen Kinderziehung, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - U.S.S.R. Trip Committee Notes, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - A New Approach to Communicating with the Russians, 1961-01-25 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Parson's Theory of Identification, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Family Structure and Personality Development, 1958-1962 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - America's Most Dangerous Prejudice, 1962-04-18 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Cross Cultural Studies of Socialization, 1963-09 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Family Structure and Personality Development, 1963-09 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - "Why Do the Russians Plant Trees along the Road?", 1963-01 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - The Making of the New Soviet Man, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Adults and Peers as Sources of Conformity and Authority, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Testimony on Economic Opportunity Act, 1964-04-23 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Maternal Deprivation, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Interesting Clippings (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Head Start Beginnings, 1965 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Some Thoughts on the Contribution of Psychology to the Improvement of International Relations (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Informing on Associates Among Soviet and American Schoolchildren (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Some Thoughts About the Changing Role of a College of Home Economics (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Soviet Methods of Upbringing and their Effects, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - "Early Deprivation in Mammals: A Cross-Species Analysis", 1966 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Pre-Adolescents - The Importance of Peers, 1967-01 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - The Psychological Costs of Quality and Equality in Education - Notes, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - The Split Level Family - Clippings and Articles (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - The Split Society: Articles (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - In the Shadow of August, 1968-11 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Ethnic Prejudice in England, France, and W. Germany (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Theory and Research in Soviet Character Education (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - The Dream of the Kibbutz, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - The Impact on Families and Children of the President's Proposals for Welfare Reform, 1969-11 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Some Psychological Aspects of Negotiation with the Soviets (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Moral Dilemma Experiment, 1969-1972 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - The Making of the New Soviet Man, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - A Place to Meet (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Reaction to Social Pressure, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - White House Conference on Children, 1970-12 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Motivational and Social Components Revised, 1968-02-01 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Comprehensive Preschool Education and Childcare Act, 1969-12-02 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Two Worlds of Childhood: U.S. and U.S.S.R. (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Two Worlds: Russell Sage (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Day Care (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Cornell Commitment and Community, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Two Worlds: Permissions (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Short and Long Term Effects of a Large Course in Behavioral Science, 1970-03-03 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Whose University?, 1970-09-10 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Preface to The Psychology of School Children, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - "On the Making of New Men", 1970 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - Statement to the Sub-Committee on Children and Youth, 1971-04-26 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Parents: Bring Up Your Children, 1971-01-26 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Who Cares for America's Children, 1971-01 (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - Children's Television Programming, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Childhood: The Roots of Alienation, 1972-10 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - The President and the Children, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - Rethinking Your Marriage, 1972-06 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Problems and Perspectives in Research in Child Development, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - A Request to Visit the People's Republic of China, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - The Case for Genetic Determinism, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - Development in Early Childhood (Box 16, Folder 60)
  - Interim Report HD&FS 115 Research Project, 1972-03 (Box 16, Folder 61)
  - Reunification With Our Children, 1972-07 (Box 16, Folder 62)
  - Testimony before Senate Sub-Committee on Children & Youth, 1973-09-25 (Box 16, Folder 63)
  - Emerging Perspectives for Research in Human Development (Box 16, Folder 64)
  - A Note on Bronfenbrenner's Moral Dilemmas, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 65)
  - Annual Volume on Human Development, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 66)
  - Social Ecology of Human Development, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 67)
  - The Changing Family and the Changing Child, 1973-02 (Box 16, Folder 68)
  - Testing Group Differences, 1973-07-09 (Box 16, Folder 69)
  - Differences in Socializing Behavior among Parents, Teachers, and Peers in Kibbutz and City, 1973-01-09 (Box 16, Folder 70)
  - Children, Families, and Social Policy: An American Perspective, 1973-04 (Box 16, Folder 71)
  - Family and Child in American Society, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 72)
  - A Theoretical Perspective for Research in Human Development, 1972-1974 (Box 16, Folder 73)
  - Alienation and Identity Research Proposal, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 74)
  - The Roots of Alienation, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 75)
  - Bronfenbrenner on Families, Schools, and Alienation, 1973-10 (Box 16, Folder 76)
  - Open Education, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 77)
  - Developmental Research and Public Policy, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 78)
  - "A Report on Longitudinal Evaluations of Preschool Programs Volume II: Is Early Intervention Effective?", 1974 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Advice to ABC on USSR, 1975-08-22 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Article Clippings (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - HD & FS 115 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Who Cares for America's Children: Versions (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The Challenge of Social Change: Multiple Versions (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Changing American Family: Commentary and Rewrite, 1975-1977 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Children and Schools: A Chinese Paradox, 1975-01-15 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Fertility and Research in the Ecology of Human Development, 1975-12 (Box 17, Folder 56)
  - Dilemma Experiment (Box 17, Folder 8)